<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>josh tregenza // designer</title>
    <description>I&#39;m Josh. I&#39;m a designer. I use my skills to help you make more money.
</description>
    <link>http://joshtregenza.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://joshtregenza.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 10:46:58 +1000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2016 10:46:58 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Freelance Guide: The Right Clients</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Unless you found a way to turn unsolicated redesigns and good intentions into money, as a freelancer, you will need to get clients and you’ll need to make sure they are the right ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book, Good to Great (A book that aged poorly as soon as the GFC struck), Jim Collins writes that “…you need to get the right people on the bus, the wrong people off the bus and the right people on the right seats”. He wrote this in regards to “great” companies and their employees but the same holds true for freelancers and their clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the tips and tricks I use to get the right clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;contracts-are-a-girls-best-friend&quot;&gt;Contracts are a Girl’s Best Friend&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a freelancer, we’re out in the world with our perverbial dicks in the wind, that is to say we are on our own. We don’t have to be though, our best friend can be our contract. Make sure you have a contract that backs you up and your interests whilst being clear and concise enough to put your client at ease.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resources like &lt;a href=&quot;https://stuffandnonsense.co.uk/projects/contract-killer/&quot;&gt;Killer Contract&lt;/a&gt; are a good place to start. You’ll want to make sure you end up sitting down with a lawyer sooner rather than later to make sure you are all covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;put-the-money-where-your-mouth-is&quot;&gt;Put the money where your mouth is&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things in your contract should be your payment structure. I think this is the easiest way to seperate the wheat from the chaff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How? I ask for 50% of the project fee upfront.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a big ask but it shows trust and dedication to your work and the project. If you haven’t done your job in selling your services then they’ll bork at this. If your prospectives aren’t willing to front the cash without a counter offer, that’s an early warning that trouble will be on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Reader if you want to learn more about my payment structure, read my article about Value Based Pricing)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;no-spec-work&quot;&gt;No Spec Work&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a prospective is asking for spec work before signing a contract, step back. That’s unpaid work, something a freelancer can’t afford to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do a few things about this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) Do the spec work, you might get the job or they might cut and run with free work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) Slap a meaty spec fee on top of their tab and get to work. When you deliver the spec work you better get that contract signed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) Thank them for your time and explain to them why you don’t do spec work. You might end up with the client anyway, if you have clear reasoning. Be ready to walk away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brings me to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;be-prepared-to-say-no&quot;&gt;Be prepared to say No&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prospectives may take advantage of you, try and negotiate a cheaper price, create unrealistic timeframes and deadlines, expect more than you can give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get that itch in the back of your head, the feeling of undue pressure, take the time to think over what they are asking and be ready to say no.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t put yourself in a position where you’ll be constricted.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 14:52:59 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://joshtregenza.com/the-right-clients</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joshtregenza.com/the-right-clients</guid>
        
        
        <category>freelance</category>
        
        <category>tips</category>
        
        <category>tricks</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hyd for my Jekyll</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had to leave the relationship. It wasn’t working out. He was too big and bloated and when things went wrong, I had no idea how to fix it. I felt like everything I did was his way. I walked out on my Wordpress site. I needed something lighter, that would give me more control. I looked out and saw many that would be suitable. I fell for a static site generator. His name was Jekyll. I knew the crowds he ran in. Knew that I could have some fun and freedom with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent nights together, the sun would greet us both, losing track of time with one another. I needed to be careful with him at times, if I didn’t watch myself, I would make a big mistake and he wouldn’t catch me. I might say the wrong thing and he wouldn’t care. Did he care about me? Can I change him so that he might? Would I be acting the role of a mad scientist in doing so?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing Jekyll after Wordpress was one of the best choice I have made for my own development. It has given me a place for me to finally tune my skills in modular structuring, Sass and the YAML syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Jekyll lacks is a GUI to streamline my writing. I have often lost productivity when I’ve tried to write. Using various programs to assist me in writing became a grind and I needed an out, I needed better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is when the idea for Hyd came to me. Why not make a simple word processor app with readibility, spelling and grammar all in the one place? For extra benefit, to Jekyll users, you can then add Front Matter tags and convert the document into Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m building Hyd as we speak, writing it in React (this project is an excuse for me to become way better at React). Once it is in a working condition I will make it open source for other to use and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Updates are forthcoming&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 14:52:59 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://joshtregenza.com/the-hyd-to-my-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joshtregenza.com/the-hyd-to-my-jekyll</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Freelance Guide: Value Based Pricing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article details why I chose value based pricing and how it helps freelancers get and keep the right clients.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 14:52:59 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://joshtregenza.com/value-based-pricing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joshtregenza.com/value-based-pricing</guid>
        
        
        <category>freelance</category>
        
        <category>tips</category>
        
        <category>tricks</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving Beyond Burnout</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Burnout… Not just a lacklustre video game, also a debilitating fallout from overworking yourself in poor conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since becoming a designer I’ve experienced it less and less but before then, it happened on an almost weekly basis. Burnout gets in the way of best laid plans. Often times I would plan out my day after a sleepless night of worry but the brick wall would have run at me by the time I had my morning coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once that happens, no matter how much I tried to get on with my work, I would feel depleted, defeated and apathetic to my financial and physical health. My mental health eroded and I would start to spiral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a situation that those I’m close to have faced as well, which causes a heavy heart. With my unfortunate expeirence in dealing with burnout I have some tips that have helped me move forward and get back to enjoying my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;give-yourself-some-set-down-time&quot;&gt;Give yourself some set down time&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What sent me into a spiral was thinking that in order to succeed I had to always be working. Makes sense, right? There are only 24 hours in a day and you need to use them all to move ahead in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;WRONG&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will move ahead in the world if you actually enjoy the world you live in. Working long hours will cause resentment and will clog your mind. Burnout swoops in when your mind is clogged, because you don’t have the mental capacity to fend it off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do one thing you enjoy every day. Doesn’t have to be much, could be dancing around to music, watching an episode of a tv show you forgot to binge or, my personal favourite, take yourself out of a date (Lord knows I love food, so the ceremony of eating has always soothed me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What ever you choose, understand that its important that you are doing it and that it isn’t a waste of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;have-one-thing-to-look-forward-to-at-the-end-of-the-day&quot;&gt;Have one thing to look forward to at the end of the day&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to work for a place that I really disliked (actually I’ve worked for several, but I digress) and that really led to daily burnout. I’d begrudingly wake up, work, eat at my desk, work more and then head home to eat a cheap meal and then go to bed. My self loathing and depression was amplified by doing this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I get through it, I took up pixel art. Each day I would look forward to making some pixel art. I would sketch out what I would do while I was heading to and from work and during my lunch. Having something that I enjoyed doing to look forward to kept me from spiralling. Nowadays I do either pixel art or 3d modelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is to have something to look forward to, find something easy to accomplish in a few hours (Or something you can work on throughout the week, the point is that you can complete something)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;talk-with-others&quot;&gt;Talk with others&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are social beasts, we may be energised from internal or external factors but socaialising with others can absolutely help. Talk to a family member, maybe a cousin you haven’t seen in a while. Talk with friends, arrange a time to catch up (This can double as something you can look forward to)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will also get you out of your own head and make you feel less isolated and alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to even talk about what you are feeling, you can be the one who asks the questions and let them do most of the talking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;is-the-present-pain-worth-the-future-pleasure&quot;&gt;Is the present pain worth the future pleasure&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was feeling burnout most of all was when I was a filmmaker, obviously that line of work wasn’t for me. That took me some time in order to convince myself that that was the case. I was a proud and depressive young man, I thought I could get through it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to know when to hold ‘em, know when to walk away and know when to run, as the saying goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked away from that industry and found real happiness with design. The take away is to question whether you are doing the thing with your time, cause if you aren’t, you’ve got to change that. I’m not saying quit tomorrow. But have the plan to quit laid out. You deserve to be happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-way-you-are-feeling-during-burnout-is-not-who-you-are&quot;&gt;The way you are feeling during burnout is not who you are&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you have been expeirencing burnout for a long period of time you may start to feel like this is what life is going to be like from now on. Don’t worry, it won’t be, I promise. You should start to feel better when you start following the above tips. As you move forward you’ll start to feel like the person you truly are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;eat-sleep-exercise-and-dont-drink&quot;&gt;Eat, sleep, exercise and don’t drink&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a tip for burnout, stress and anxiety and has helped me countless times. When you are feeling the burn…out have a filling meal, go for a run, try and get a good night’s sleep and take a break from coffee and alcohol until you are in a better place. You’ll feel better centred and more atuned .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not a health care professional, I’m a auto-didact designer who’s had a few rounds in the ring and many more to come. I do want to help people, that’s why I’m sharing with you, the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are all in this together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 14:52:59 +1000</pubDate>
        <link>http://joshtregenza.com/dealing-with-burnout</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://joshtregenza.com/dealing-with-burnout</guid>
        
        
        <category>design</category>
        
        <category>work</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
